拳王 来吧 你不是这样糟的
Come on, champ. You ain't so bad!
放马过来！
Come on!
来啊！
你输了！
You're out!
《洛奇4》
我们协议过
We made a deal.
我知道 但这真是太疯狂
I know, but this is extremely crazy.
是啊 精神不正常
Yeah, it's mentally irregular.
有道理的
But it makes sense.
你欠我一个人情
You owe me a favor.
我知道 但你何时想到的？
I know, but when did you think of this?
大约三年前
About three years ago.
这真是太疯狂了 阿波罗
This is very crazy, Apollo.
听着 牡马
Look, Stallion.
你上次以一秒之差胜出
you won that last fight by one second.
是一秒
You beat me by one second.
即使聪明如我也难以应付
That's very hard for a man of my intelligence to handle.
是吗 你不是说过
Is it? Didn't you say afterwards.
已学会怎样应付吗
you learned how to live with it?
- 骗你的 - 你骗我
- I lied. - You lied.
那么此刻你要证明给自己看
So now you have to prove it to yourself?
没错 不要电视 不要报章
Just for myself. No TV or newspapers,
只须你和我
just you and me.
只是你和我
Nothing. Just you and me.
- 老人先请吧 - 随你怎说 孩子
- Age before beauty - Anything you say, son.
一切交给我办吧
I do all the work.
你还是慢慢来
You better go slow.
因为你不再年轻力壮
You ain't as young as springtime no more.
我仍然可以给你颜色的
I'm still young enough to whip your butt.
是吗 你要怎样做
Yeah? How will you do that?
你已把一切传授给我
You taught me everything you know.
几乎一切
Almost everything.
别忘记 你斗得狠
Remember, you fight great.
但我是一个斗士 准备好了吗
but I'm a great fighter, you ready.
- 当然 - 好的
- Absolutely. - All right.
你知道吗 牡马
You know, Stallion.
我们老了实在太可惜 对吗
It's too bad we have to get old, yeah?
只管出拳吧 阿波罗
Just keep punching, Apollo.
不用摇铃吗
Want to ring the bell?
好吧
All right.
放马过来！
Come on!
来吧！
以你这把年纪仍能这样灵活
You really move good for an older guy.
- 简直可以飞 - 小心
- Look at him fly. - Look out.
不 别给我击中
No, you don't want any of this.
或许我找错了对手
Maybe I'm in here with the wrong guy.
爸爸 你迟到
Dad, you're late.
妈妈一定会骂你
Mom's going to yell at you.
- 你好吗？- 很好
- How you doing? - Fine.
你不觉得有点亮了吗？
Don't you think that's a little bright? A little bit.
那帽子从何处来的？
Where'd you get that hat?
朋友给我的 喜欢吗？
A friend gave it to me. Like it?
谁打了你的眼睛？
Who punched you in the eye?
同一个朋友
Same friend.
真奇怪 快些进来 爸爸
That's weird. Better hurry, Dad.
知道吗 你正养成一个大声说话的个性
You know, you're developing a very loud personality.
别走太快 否则你会到焦点的外面
Don't go too fast or you'll get out of focus.
是吗？
Really?
你好
Yo.
你好 时候也差不多
Yo, It's about time.
对不起我迟了
I'm sorry I'm late.
过去那边准备吃饭 好吗？
Why don't you get ready to eat, ok?
你回来了 不用在叫他名字了
You're here. Now stop calling him name.
你一直在喊着我的名字？
You been calling me names?
我们再等下去就会变成下一个生日
We wait any longer, it will be my next birthday.
你去哪儿了？
Where have you been?
出去打拳
Out getting punched.
把蛋糕拿过来
Bring the cake in here,
我们开始庆祝
and let's get the celebration underway.
我很饿
I'm hungry.
宝贝 拿蛋糕来 他一定喜欢的
Babe, get the cake. He'll love it.
我们有大惊喜给你
We have a great surprise for you.
一定喜欢这蛋糕 是吧
You'll love this cake, ok?
你会喜欢这份礼物的 泡利叔叔
You'll love your present, Uncle Paulie.
在哪里？
Where is it?
让我先营造气氛 把灯光较暗
Let me set the mood here. I have to turn the lights down.
看着
Watch this.
停在行车道吗？
It's parked in the driveway?
耐心一点好吗？
Just be patient, would you?
我很紧张 开始冒汗了
I'm so excited, I'm sweating.
我觉着像我要打一场大的拳赛
I feel like I'm going into a big fight.
生日快乐 保利
Happy birthday, Paulie.
这是什么？
What the hell is this?
你的礼物
Your present.
我想要一辆跑车
I wanted a sports car for my birthday.
不是一个会走路的垃圾箱
not a walking trash can.
得了 它蛮不错的
Come on, he looks great here.
它非常古怪
This is extremely psycho.
你没有朋友 所以我们认为你会喜欢它
Since you don't have any friends, we thought you'd like it.
对 假装开心好吗？孤单的时候它可以和你作伴
Yeah. Pretend you're happy. It'll keep you company when you're all alone.
看上去还不错
That's a great-looking guy.
请许愿
Please make a wish.
很可怕 它会说话
It's creepy! That thing talks!
可怕？它太棒了 我很希望在我成长时 就能有它了
Creepy? These things are great! I wish I had one when I was growing up.
就像它说的 快许个愿
Make a wish, like he said.
我希望没作过这噩梦
I wish I wasn't in this nightmare.
很有格调的愿望 很好
A very classy wish.
你认为呢？
What do you think?
非常好吧
Very good.
一起吹熄蜡烛好吗？
Want to help me put out this forest fire?
没问题
Sure.
我数三声 一
On the count of three. One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
熄灭了
They're out.
你淹死我了
You drowned me!
别担心
Don't worry.
保利 我替你弄干净
I'll clean it up for you, Paulie.
洛奇
Rocky.
给你发觉了
Yeah, you noticed.
你捧着那蛋糕做什么？
What are you doing with that cake?
派对还未完的
The party ain't over yet.
还要继续庆祝
Still got to celebrate.
这一晚很特别
It's a special night.
对 是星期三
Yeah, it's Wednesday.
的确是星期三
It's definitely Wednesday.
但你别忘记
but in case you forgot.
我们结婚已经九年了
it's almost been nine years since you married me.
这是送给你的
so here's your prize.
但下星期才是我们的周年纪念
But our anniversary's a week away.
没错 但为何要等？
That's true. But why wait?
- 它很粗糙？- 不是
- Has it been that rough? - No.
是非常好 真的
It's been excellent.
快打开你的礼物 快
Open your prize. Go on.
好的
All right.
喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
- 很美 - 那就好了
- It's beautiful. - All right.
我不知 不知有多担心
I was so nervous. I didn't know.
希望你喜欢
I hope you like it.
卖给我的那傢伙说
The guy I bought it from says.
虽然它看似蛇 但放心
even if it looks like a snake, don't worry.
它不会咬你的
It won't bite you.
很美丽
It's beautiful.
知道什么是最棒吗？
You know what's amazing?
经过了这么多年
After all these years.
我感到一切仍是新的
everything still seems kind of new.
记得很久以前 我曾告诉你
You remember a long time ago I told you that.
我说你永远甩不掉我
you ain't never getting rid of me.
记得吗？
remember that?
你的确没有
You're not.
你永不会离开我
You're never getting rid of me.
周年纪念快乐
Happy almost anniversary.
可否回答一些问题？
Can you answer a few questions?
你会逗留多久？
How long you here for?
迟些会公布
We talk later, please.
伊凡 你何时会出战？
When are you fighting, Drago?
迟些再谈
We talk it later.
苏联真的会
Is it definite the Soviet Union.
加入职业拳赛吗？
will enter professional boxing?
无可奉告
Please, no more talk now.
我们会在记者招待会公布
We will talk at press conference.
那会在什么地方举行？
Do you know where it will be held?
迟些会公布
We talk it later.
今天或许是运动史上的一个里程碑
Today may have proved to be a landmark in sports history.
经过多年的混乱政局后
After unraveling years of red tape,
俄罗斯终于参加竞赛
Russia will now throw its hat into the ring.
指的是职业拳击赛
The prize ring, that is.
以下由他太太积米拉来介绍她丈夫
The introductions were made by his wife Ludmilla Vobet Drago.
她是游泳金牌得主
She was the double gold medalist in swimming.
今天 苏联已经加入职业拳击界
Today the Soviet Union has officially entered professional boxing.
我丈夫就是无敌的重量级业余世界拳王
My husband and great undefeated heavyweight world amateur champion.
伊凡
Captain Ivan Drago…
他与他的教练来到美国
has come with his trainers to America.
参予国际运动比赛和作为亲善大使
to compete as an international sportsman and ambassador of goodwill.
伊凡有打过职业拳赛吗
Has Drago ever boxed against a real professional?
他在俄罗斯跟享负盛名的韦曼纽训练
From having been trained in Russia by great boxing coach, Manuel Vega.
现任教练为廉沙基 我们希望他有资格做拳王
and now by Sergei Rimsky, we hope he's qualified to do so.
希望？
Hope?
他当然有资格 但我不想说得太自信
Well, I know he is, but I don't want to sound too confident.
若可以的话 我们想
If possible, we would like to.
他与拳王鲍洛奇进行一场表演赛
have an exhibition bout with your famous champion Rocky Balboa.
什么使你认为他能迎战经验丰富的洛奇？
What makes you think he can fight someone as seasoned as Balboa?
没有人比得上他的力量 他的耐力
No one can match his strength, his endurance.
和他的野心
or his aggressiveness.
听上去他不可战胜
You sound like he's indestructible.
他的确是
Yes, he is.
俄罗斯猛犸象
Well. Can this mammoth Russian,
这个绰号「西伯利亚快车」的
already nicknamed the Siberian Express,
能否改变重量级职业拳击的排名？
wreak havoc among the professional heavyweight ranks?
无论谁是他第一个对手
Whoever he fights first,
那将会是场激战
it'll be one hot ticket.
接下来我们将报道今天职业足球赛的成绩
We'll be right back with a check on today's pro football scoreboard.
爸爸 我什么时侯可以学打拳？
Dad, when can I learn to fight?
我听不到 你说什么？
I can't hear you. What?
我想学打拳
I want to learn to fight.
把机器人的音量调低好吗？
Could you turn your robot down?
你看我打拳已经足够
You see I fight,
所以你不用打
so you don't have to fight.
我想你靠脑袋做事
I want you to use your head for something.
不要像我这样打沙包
instead of a punching bag like I do.
你的脑袋也不像沙包
Your head doesn't look like a punching bag.
不像吗？很感谢
That's nice. Thanks a lot.
它像棒球接手的手套
It looks like a catcher's mitt.
好聪明
A wise guy.
巴尔博亚先生 奎迪先生的电话
Mr. Balboa, Mr. Creed's on the phone.
我马上来听
Yeah? I'll be right there.
你可以在这里听
You can get it right here.
希望不是又一场复赛
I hope it's not another rematch.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
- 什么事 - 阿波罗
- Hello? - Yeah, Apollo.
关掉它 你好吗？
Turn that down. How are you doing?
什么？你出来？
Yeah? You're coming out?
太好了 我在做什么？
That's great. What am I doing?
我感到很眼晕
I'm just getting dizzy.
我丈夫和我感谢各位来到我们的训练中心
My husband and I thank you for coming to our training quarters today.
正如你们所见 这里非常先进
As you can see, it is highly advanced.
并且我们愿意让美国报界报道
and we wish to show the American press a small portion.
我们的国家在提高人类能力的技术上
of the advances our country's made.
所得到的成就
in the technology of human performance.
廉教练 这些仪器怎样增强人的能力？
Coach Rimsky, what does all this do to enhance performance?
- 那… - 我替你回答
- Well… - If I may answer.
通过激发他的全力
It makes a man a better man.
他将会变成更出色 无可匹敌的运动员
a great athlete a super athlete by harnessing all his strength.
虽然大多数国家都忽视体热学
Though most of the world is ignorant in body chemistry,
但我们希望把这知识灌输给你们
we wish to educate your country.
谣传苏联运动员使用兴奋剂
There have been rumors of doping.
和注射合成代谢类固醇
and distribution of anabolic steroids in the Soviet Union.
伊凡有参与这些实验吗？
Has Drago partaken in any such experiments?
没有 伊凡是采用自然训练法的
No, Ivan in naturally trained.
那你怎解释他异常的力量？
Then how do you explain his freakish strength?
像大力水手一样 他每天都吃菠菜
Like your Popeye, he ate his spinach every day.
要示范一下吗？
Shall we have a demonstration?
- 请 - 谢谢
- Please do. - Thank you.
一个正常重量级拳手
A normal heavyweight.
每平方英寸能击出700磅力量
averages 700 pounds of pressure per square inch.
伊凡做出1850磅
Drago averages 1850 pounds.
所以结果显而易见
So the result is quite obvious.
什么结果呢？
What results are those?
不论他打什么 都会被毁灭
Whatever he hits, he destroys.
他很高大强壮 但也笨拙
He's big and he's strong, but he's clumsy.
我知道我可以击败他
I know I can beat him.
你为何又想打拳？
Why do you want to fight again?
这是我一种信念
It's something I believe in.
你去做功课
You can do your homework.
好吧 迟些见 爸爸
Okay. Later, Dad.
晚会见 叔叔们
Later, Uncle Paulie, Apollo.
- 一会儿见 大人物 - 一会儿见 孩子
- Later, big man. - See you later, kiddo.
你不认为大家都期望见到洛奇第一个击倒他？
Don't you think people are expecting to see Rocky whack this bum out first?
对 到真正比赛时会的
Yeah, and he will when it's for real.
但这只是表演赛 不是认真的
This is just an exhibition bout. It's kid stuff.
那目的是什么？
What's the purpose?
什么值得去受伤？
What's worth getting hurt for?
那是什么东西？
What the hell is that?
是我女朋友
That's my girl.
- 谢谢 宝贝 - 别客气
- Thanks, honey. - You're welcome.
这首歌很好听
Nice song.
是我最喜欢的 你是最棒的
It's my favorite. You're the greatest.
再见
See you, sport.
See you.
保利 谁教它这样说话的？
Paulie, who taught it to talk like that?
她爱我
She loves me.
我也说过
Like I was saying,
我不会让这个大肆宣传的傻瓜
I don't want this chump to come here with all that hype.
使我们被看扁
trying to make us look bad.
他们出尽各种花招
They try every other way.
在洛奇协助下 我们会得到传媒报导
With Rock's help, we can get great media coverage,
使他们被比下去
We can make them look bad.
这样做不对
I think it's wrong.
没什么比这做得更对
It's never been more right.
你是个出色的拳手
You're a great fighter,
但你已经退役5年了
but you've been retired for five years.
你不觉着是时候想想其他事了？
Don't you think it's time to think about something else?
你还可以捱多少拳？
How much can you take?
还有你
Either of you.
我去冲咖啡
I'll get the coffee.
对不起 我没有别的意思
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
我只是担心你俩
I just care about you both.
有看过这些漫画吗？
You ever try these comics?
没有
No.
能让你保持生殖力
Keeps your fertility.
保利
Paulie.
这比赛真精彩
This was a great fight.
精彩？我快被打晕了 你看
Great? I'm getting punchy just watching.
你的下巴怎会被打中的 杜马
What you using for a chin there, Stallion?
我应该闪过的
I should have slipped that one.
是啊 你绝对闪得过
Yeah, You definitely should have slipped.
知道吗 你在拳台上流血时人们对你很疯狂
It's crazy how people care about you when you're in that ring bleeding,
但一旦你踏出擂台 你就变成历史
but once you step out of that ring, you're ancient history.
你不是历史
You ain't ancient history.
没人向我要签名
Nobody's asking for autographs.
阿波罗 可以问你些事情吗？
Apollo, Can I ask you something?
什么？
What?
你明白要跟伊凡打的拳赛
You know this fight you're having against the Russian.
其实并非真的要对付他？
Do you think maybe it ain't against him?
不是他 那是谁？
If it's not him, then who is it against?
会不会是你自己对自己？
Do you think maybe it's like you against you?
当然不是 我觉着你大脑确实受伤了
No, I think you really are getting brain damaged.
我真的这样想
That's what I think.
或许吧 但是
Yeah, maybe, but.
阿波罗 我不是说笑的
I'm speaking the truth, Apollo.
- 是吗？- 是
- Are you? - Yeah.
我不想听到这样的话
I don't think I want to hear this.
得了 阿波罗
Come on, Apollo.
你是个出色的拳手 毋庸置疑
you're a great fighter. No doubt about that.
但是我们也必须面对现实
But we have to face the facts too.
你不想相信 但那的确已经结束了
You don't want to believe it, but maybe the show is over.
你说得容易 因为你仍然是拳王
That's easy for you to say. You're still on top.
当你不再是拳王时 你会怎样？
What happens when you're not on top? Then what?
我们会到什么地方？因为我们不会再重生
Where do we go? We sure can't be born again.
没错 但是我们有时可以转变的
I know we can't be born again, but we have to change sometime.
我不想变 我喜欢当拳手
I don't want to change! I like who I am!
我也喜欢你当拳手 但你想想
I like who you are too, but look at that.
即使你不想相信 也改变不了现实
You don't want to believe this, but that ain't us no more.
我们无法再像以前一样
We can't do that the way we did before.
我们在变 我们在变回正常人
We're changing. We're turning into regular people.
不 或者你以为你在变
No, maybe you think you're changing.
但你无法改变你是谁
but you can't change what you really are.
不会忘记奖金等东西 什么也没改变
Forget all this money and stuff around you. It don't change a thing.
你与我甚至都没有选择
You and me don't even have a choice.
我们天生残酷
We're born with a killer instinct,
不可能像收音机那样随便开关的
you can't turn off and on like a radio.
我们必须作战 因为我们是战士
We have to be in the middle of the action because we're warriors.
没有挑战 没有战争
Without some challenge, without some war to fight.
战士就跟死人没分别
then the warrior may as well be dead.
我请求你
So I'm asking you,
作为一个朋友
as a friend,
最后一次支持我
stand by my side this one last time.
你的口才真了得 阿波罗
You're a great talker, Apollo.
好吧 但这何时完结
All right, but when this is over.
你最了解我的 杜马
You know me, Stallion.
我总是想到别的事
I always think of something else.
那才使我害怕
That's what I'm afraid of.
好吧 我答应你
All right, you have a deal.
我为那傢伙感到遗憾了
I feel sorry for that guy.
你为何决定 跟伊凡进行表演赛？
Apollo, what made you decide to put on an exhibition with Drago?
是一种责任感吧
Call it a sense of responsibility.
责任感 为什么？
Responsibility, how?
我必须教这小子 如何打美式拳击
I have to teach this young fellow how to box American style.
伊凡不是欠缺一些经验吗？
Isn't Drago a little inexperienced to be in the same ring?
一些傢伙要从苦中学习的
Some folks have to learn the hard way.
不会立即把他击倒？
No knockout prediction?
不 他没使我恼火
I'm not angry with him.
我只想让全世界知道
I just want to show the world.
俄罗斯没有拥有最好的运动员
Russia doesn't have all the best athletes.
洛奇 你赞成阿波罗跟伊凡对赛吗？
How do you think Apollo should fight Drago?
我个人认为 最重要的是你需要个梯子
Personally, the first thing you need is a ladder.
伊凡 要跟前拳王比赛有什么感觉？
How does it feel to spar with the great former champion?
他没带舌头到美国来
The man's tongue didn't come through customs.
我丈夫很高兴有这个机会
My husband is very happy to have this opportunity.
这是他的梦想
It's his dream.
梦想 这是什么意思？
Dream. How do you mean?
阿波罗这名字在俄罗斯 是很出名和备受尊崇的
In our country, Apollo Creed is well-known and very respected.
这次可是我们的胜利
It could be a good victory.
等一等 胜利？
Wait a minute. Win?
你不是认为可以打败我吧？
You don't really think you're going to whip me, do you?
他来不是为了输的
He didn't come here to lose.
女士 你等一下
You hold on, little lady.
因为他将会败给我
Lose and lose royally he will do.
你为何这样肯定？
How can you be so sure?
我曾跟最出色的拳手比赛 他曾打败他们
I've been with best, I've beaten the best.
我打败过的人比社会保障下还多
I've retired more men than Social Security.
不好意思
Excuse, please.
似乎你不是太现实 对吧？
You are not very realistic.
你是什么人？
Where did you come from?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你是懂拳击
You can box, yes,
但你太老了 不是伊凡对手
but you are far too old to think you can win over Drago.
是这样吗？
Is that a fact?
对 这是残酷的事实
Yes, and it could be a painful one.
你把这个没蛋蛋的木头人到拳场
You put that heavy bag without balls in the ring with me.
你就明白什么叫残酷
and you'll see the meaning of pain!
你为何侮辱我们？
Why do you insult us?
请你冷静点
You just hold on here.
不要逼我做坏人
Don't make me out as the bad guy.
我来是谈友谊赛 直到你先挑衅
I came to talk about a friendly exhibition bout till you started up.
惹事的是这位多嘴同志
Come right the big mouth body.
很明显 挑衅的是你
You are the aggressor! This is obvious!
各位传媒朋友 在公平起见下
I wish to say to the press in all fairness,
伊凡不应跟这个人比赛
Drago should not even fight this man,
因为他已经过时！
He is a has-been!
立刻叫那木头跟我到拳场！
You get that big chump in the ring right now!
让他来 我不想听她说
Bring it on. I don't want to hear her.
叫那笨蛋来
Just let that chump go.
好吧
All right.
我已说出我的感觉
I said what I feel.
擂台上自会分出胜负
We'll finish this in the ring.
- 明白吗 - 随你喜欢
- You understand? - Whatever you like.
住口 还有你带来的这些傀儡也是
You and all your puppets just shut up!
你才过时 木头人
You are history, chump.
我刚才怎样
How did I do?
吵了少许
A little loud for my taste.
- 但不错吧 - 非常好
- But good? - Yeah, very good.
欢迎各位来到灯光之城
Welcome one and all to the city of lights.
拉斯维加斯
Las Vegas,
参予这次特别盛事
and one of the most unusual events in years.
东西方对对碰
East meets West.
老手与新手进行一场友谊拳赛
Age versus youth in a goodwill exhibition match.
前拳王阿波罗奎迪
as the former champion Apollo Creed.
对来自苏联 满身肌肉的
takes on a mountain of muscle from the Soviet Union.
伊凡
Ivan Drago.
- 来吧 - 忍耐是美德
- Come on. - Patience is a virtue.
我已准备出击
I'm ready to rock and roll.
我明白 但你先要拿装备 可以了
I understand, but you need your equipment. There you go.
你看似木乃伊
Now you look like a mummy.
- 我像木乃伊 - 感到怎样？
- I feel like a mummy. - Does it feel okay?
很好 连钉子也可吞下
It feels great. I could eat nails.
我从没有吃过
I never tried them things.
你说什么？
What?
我从没吃过蜗牛
I never had snails.
我在花园见过蜗牛 但我从没吃过
I seen them in the garden, but I never wanted to eat them.
我不是说蜗牛 我说钉子
I didn't say anything about snails. I said, "nails, "
钉子 杜马
Nail. Stallion. Yeah.
你状态很好
You look pretty good.
但当比赛开始时 答应我一件事
but do me a favor when you go up there.
不要逞强 可以吗
Try not to wear yourself out.
逞强 当然
Yeah, wear myself out.
你已经五年没有比赛
It's just that you haven't been in the ring for five years.
所以我只想你保持
I just want you to maintain a bit.
什么？我不是老头子
You sound like I'm an old man.
我正处于最佳状态 更强壮 反应更快
I'm in the best shape of my life. I'm stronger. I'm quicker.
我不是说你不在状态
I'm not saying you're not ready.
但换了是我
but, personally, if it were me.
我会押后数星期才比赛
I wouldn't mind postponing it a couple weeks.
- 押后？- 对 我指
- Postpone? - Yeah.
我们对这小子毫不认识
Come on, we don't really know anything about this guy you're fighting.
好吧 即使我说押后
Let's say I postpone.
我退出 让别人跟这个木头打
I pull out, somebody else steps in and whips this chump.
- 那我怎样 - 你是什么意思
- Where does that leave me? - What do you mean?
这只不过是表演赛
It's just some exhibition fight.
没什么大不了
This don't mean nothing.
不 你这样想就错了
No, that's where you're wrong.
这不是一场无关痛痒的表演赛
This is not just an exhibition that doesn't mean anything.
我们要对付他们 你明白吗？
This is us against them. Come on.
牡马
Stallion.
此刻你或许不明白
maybe you don't know.
我现在说的话
what I'm talking about now.
但当比赛完了你就会明白
but you will when it's over.
相信我 到时你会明白
Believe me, you will when it's over!
伊凡
Drago.
祝你好运
Good luck.
希望赛后我们可以做朋友
I hope after we can be friend.
我也希望
I hope so.
当然
Of course.
他们是运动员 而不是士兵
They're sportsmen, not soldiers.
慢慢欣赏
Enjoy the fight.
各位 晚上好
Good evening, everyone.
我赖士图与禾华纳
Along with Warner Wolf, I'm Stu Nahan.
欢迎大家收看这场特别盛事
We welcome you to a most unusual event.
这是职业拳击界史上
For the first time,
首次东西对垒
West against East in professional sports.
谢谢你支持我
Thanks for getting me here.
我欠你一个人情
I owe you one.
不 大家打平了
No, we're even.
我感到重生一样
God, I feel born again.
女士们先生们 欢迎各位
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome.
有请我们真正的拳王
I would like to announce the presence of a true fighting champion.
充分表现「坚毅」二字的
that defines the word courage.
意大利牡马鲍洛奇
The Italian Stallion, Rocky Balboa.
借过 好吗
Excuse me, would you.
随便
Certainly.
洛奇
Rocky.
今晚的特别赛事
Tonight's special event features.
有两位特别的选手
two great athletes.
在蓝色场角的是体重221磅
In the blue corner weighing 221 pounds.
前世界重量级拳王
the former heavyweight champion of the world.
跳跃的毁灭者
the Dancing Destroyer.
刺痛之王
the King of Sting.
拳击伯爵
the Count of Monte Fisto.
这么多绰号
You think you have enough names?
耐心一点 快读完了
Be patient. We're almost done.
灾难大师 独一无二的
The Master of Disaster, the one and only.
阿波罗 奎迪
Apollo Creed!
观众都期待一场激战
The crowd anticipating a great fight.
阿波罗已在台上
Apollo is playing to the crowd.
在红色场角的
In the red corner.
是体重261磅
weighing an even 261 pounds.
金牌得主 兼长胜的业余世界冠军
gold medalist and undefeated world amateur champion.
来自苏联的
from the Soviet Union.
西伯利亚火牛
the Siberian Bull.
伊凡
Ivan Drago!
吃定你了
I want you!
两位拳手都走到擂台中央
The two fighters come to the center of the ring.
听候裁判费路的指示
for the instructions from referee Lou Filippo.
你们已明白规例
You boys know the rules.
不许击打腰部以下 肾部 后脑
Watch your low blows, kidney punches, rabbit punches.
若把对方击倒
In case of a knockdown,
就要返回场角
you go to the corner I tell you.
直至听到我指示才出来
and you stay there until I tell you to come out.
双方握手 公平决斗
Shake hands and let's have a good fight.
是时候好好学习了 小子
It's time to go to school, son.
提起双手
Get your hands up.
你还要个翻译吗
Do you need an interpreter?
是时候学习
It's time to go to school.
你会输
You will lose.
好吧
All right.
他们之间的仇恨
The bad blood between these two.
弥漫着整个场馆
can be felt all over this arena.
这位俄罗斯人的身型让我惊讶
I can't get over the size of this Russian.
看我表现吧
It's show time!
不好意思
Excuse me.
你忘记了戴？
Didn't you forget something?
来
Come on.
阿波罗今晚似乎斗志高昂
Apollo seems to be in great spirits tonight.
他真的没叫观众失望
He's really putting on a show for this capacity crowd.
稍后回来
Be back in a minute.
第一回合
Round one.
奎迪轻快地移动 现在向后移
Creed dancing around Creed backpedaling now.
他已经五年没比赛
He's been away five years.
别等他 先出击
Don't wait him, get out first.
来吧
Come on.
两位拳手都来进攻
Neither fighter ready to throw a punch.
左刺拳
A left jab there.
奎迪再挥左刺拳
A left jab once again by Creed.
奎迪滑了一下
A slip by Creed.
真古怪
This is bizarre.
奎迪是拳王
Creed is over the hill,
而这个俄罗斯人则从没比赛过
and the Russian hasn't fought anybody.
别停下来 刺拳打他
Keep moving! Stick him! Apollo.
伊凡再次进攻
Drago moving in again.
奎迪再挥出左拳 伊凡避开
A left hand by Creed and another. Drago moves away.
好吧 来
Come on.
出拳
Get your hands up!
奎迪再次挥出左拳
Another left hand by Creed!
伊凡在伺机用右手攻击
Drago waiting, cocking that right hand.
快避开！
Get out there!
避开他 别靠近他
Get out of there!
再来一个左拳
And a left hand!
他在不断狂揍！
He's taking some punishment now!
伊凡迫使他到围绳！
Drago moves him against the ropes!
别让他脱身！
Tie him up now!
伊凡把奎迪逼到另一边！
Now the Russian throws Creed across the ring!
出来！
Move!
伊凡挥出上勾拳！
It is Drago with the upper hand!
他再用左拳击中上腹！
Drago with a left to the midsection!
快走到中间！
Get out of that corner!
伊凡不断挥出右拳！
Another right and another right!
又挥出另一个右拳！
Another right, another right!
但奎迪已被逼到围绳！
Creed is against the ropes!
他们上台阻止他们！
They step in and stop it!
你们在做什么？
What are you guys doing?
这只是一场表演赛 明白吗？
This is supposed to be an exhibition! You understand?
只是表演赛！
Just an exhibition!
伊凡漂亮地赛完第一回合
A tremendous end to the first round by the Russian.
阿波罗血流满面
And a very bloody Apollo Creed.
这位苏联拳手的力量真惊人！
The Soviet's strength is incredible!
我要终止比赛
Champ, I have to stop you.
这拳赛已完结 我要终止它
This fight's finished. I have to call it.
你无法再继续比赛
Champ, you can't do no more out there.
我来是拳斗的
I'm here to fight.
他要打死你 我得阻止
He's killing you. I have to stop this thing.
我要继续
I'm here to fight.
答应我不要终止赛事
Promise me you won't stop this fight.
这真是前拳王灾难性的一个回合
That was a pulverizing round for the ex-champion.
伊凡果然很认真
Ivan Drago is definitely for real.
无论怎样 不要终止比赛
Don't stop this fight no matter what.
无论怎么样
no matter what.
奎迪迎战第二回合 他在轻快移动
Creed comes out for round two, dancing around.
双脚似乎仍充满弹跳力
The legs appear to be still a little rubbery.
提起双手
Get your hands up.
伊凡未有行动
Now it is the Russian just standing there.
他企图恫吓奎迪
The Russian trying to intimidate Creed.
伊凡以右拳还击 奎迪摇摇摆摆
The Russian throws a right hand and staggers Creed!
又一个击中奎迪的下颚！
Another right to the jaw!
再用左拳打其头部！
A left to the head!
伊凡完全不手下留情！
Creed is being pounded without mercy!
不要再打！
Stop the fight!
裁判企图阻止
The referee tries to step in.
他被撵到另一边
and he's thrown across the ring!
抛毛巾！
Throw the towel!
不
No.
我从没见过阿波罗这样捱打！
I have never seen Apollo take so much punishment!
把毛巾抛出！
Throw the damn towel!
不
No.
天啊！
My God!
奎迪倒下来了！
Creed is down!
阿波罗倒下来 他可能受重伤
Apollo could be badly hurt.
让他透透气！
Let him breathe!
- 让开 - 叫他们退后
- Get move back. - Get these guys out of here!
胜出的是伊凡
The winner: Ivan Drago.
让我过去 阿波罗
Let me through! Apollo!
我是不会给打败的
I cannot be defeated.
- 他没事吗？- 快找医生来！
- Is he okay? - Somebody get a doctor!
奎迪没动静
There is no movement by Creed.
把灯关掉！
Get that light off him!
我打败所有人
I defeat all men.
- 他死了吗？- 走开！
- Is he dead? - Get out of here!
现场一片混乱！
It's absolute pandemonium!
请退后
Stand back.
让他透气 阿波罗！
Let him breathe!
你没有事的
You can do it.
很快
Soon.
我就会打败真正拳王
I defeat real champion.
担架呢？
Where's the stretcher?
让他呼吸
Let him breathe!
本来是以喜剧开场 最后却以悲剧收场
What started out as a joke has turned out to be a disaster.
他的伤势似乎很严重
Creed appears to be in very serious condition.
他仍活着吗？
Is the man alive?
你会没事的 阿波罗
You can make it, Apollo.
他要死就死了吧
If he dies, he dies.
我有好多关于这个人的话可说
There's a lot I could say about this man.
但现在都不重要
I don't know if it matters now.
重要的是
I guess what matters is.
他代表的是什么
what he stood for.
他为了什么而活
what he lived for.
及他为了什么而死
and what he died for.
你做所有的事情
You always did everything.
总是按你喜欢的方式
the way you wanted it.
当时我不明白 但是
I didn't understand that, but.
现在我明白了
now I understand.
我永不会忘记你 阿波罗
I'll never forget you, Apollo.
你是最优秀的
You're the best.
洛奇 这是最后决定吗？
Rocky, is the decision final?
是
Yes.
这是首次有拳王放弃名衔吗？
Are you the first to give up his crown?
我可不知道
I don't know about that.
锦标对你来说还有意义吗？
Doesn the title mean anything to you anymore?
没有 直到这比赛完结
Not until this is over.
廉教练 洛奇以挥拳力量劲而著称
Coach Rimsky, considering Rocky's known punching power.
你认为这比赛易应付吗？
do you still think this will be an easy fight?
当然 这是体型
Yes, of course. It's a matter of size.
与进化的问题 不是吗？
and evolution. Isn't it, gentlemen?
伊凡是历来训练得最完美运动员
Drago is the most perfectly trained athlete ever.
那个傢伙根本没有那身型或耐力
This other man has not the size or the endurance.
又或者天赋以胜出
or the genetics to win.
在体力方面他根本无法取胜
It's physically impossible for this little man to win.
伊凡是未来的希望
Drago is a look at the future.
这点从没被提过 这拳赛有多少奖金？
There's been no mention yet, but how much are you making for this fight?
没奖金
No money.
这跟钱无关
It's not about money.
已定了比赛日期吗？
Has the fight date been set yet?
12月25日
December 25.
为何拣圣诞节？
Why Christmas?
- 有人通知我的 - 在哪里举行？
- That's what I was told. - Where?
在俄罗斯
It's in Russia.
你疯了吗？
Are you nuts?
洛奇 怎么了？
What's going on?
你为何答应？
Why did you agree to this?
除了在苏联 没有其他地方可以
We fight in Soviet Union or we fight nowhere.
为什么你们不问伊凡的妻子为何害怕
Why don't you ask Drago's wife why she is afraid?
告诉他们为什么
Tell them, please.
我怕我丈夫有生命危险
I'm afraid for my husband's life.
到处都有暴力恐吓
We have threats of violence everywhere.
我们不是政客
We are not in politics.
我只想我丈夫安全并获公平对待
All I want is for my husband to be safe, to be treated fairly.
你们叫他做杀手
You call him a killer.
他是职业拳手 不是杀手
He's a professional fighter, not a killer.
你们深信比我们优秀
You have this belief that you are better than us.
你们深信这国家非常好
You have this belief that this country is so very good.
而我国就非常糟
and we are so very bad.
你们深信你们公平
You have this belief that you are so fair.
而我们非常无情
and we are so cruel.
这一切都是谎话和谣传
It's all lies and false propaganda.
只是为了支持这个敌对的及暴力的政府！
to support this antagonistic and violent government!
「暴力」？
"Violent"?
我们没有用机关枪来恐吓人民
We don't keep our people behind a wall with machine guns.
- 你是谁？- 我是谁？
- Who are you? - Who am I?
我是不沉默的大多数 大嘴怪！
I'm the unsilent majority, big mouth!
说得好！
Good!
侮辱我们！
Yes, insult us!
这是典型的对待外国人的无礼表现
It's more typical rude behavior toward visiting foreigners.
或者这次击败 这个所谓冠军的家伙
But perhaps this simple defeat of this little so-called champion.
会是一个非常好的例子
will be a perfect example.
说明你们的社会已变得多么无能
of how pathetic and weak your society has become!
我们走
We go!
鲍太太
Mrs. Balboa!
你对到俄罗斯比赛有何感想？
How do you feel about going to Russia?
对这个受争议的决定有何看法？
How does it feel to be part of such a controversial decision?
是因为奎迪的死吗？
Did Creed's death make up your husband's mind?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
为何要在圣诞节比赛？
why will fight in Christmas?
是他决定的吗？
Is it his decision?
你何时会去俄罗斯？
When will you go to Russia?
我不会去俄罗斯 我不知道你们在说什么
I'm not going to Russia. I don't know what you're talking about.
我也不知道你们来做什么
or what you people are doing here.
你没事吗？
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
很好
Fine.
你为何这样做？
Why did you do it?
我只是做我要做的事
I just have to do what I have to do.
你什么也不需要做
You don't have to do anything.
艾莉 我需要
No, Adrian, I do.
而且还要离开这地方
I have to leave this place too.
你要去哪里？
So where are you going?
他们说让我到俄罗斯受训
They said they would let me train in Russia.
我只想到一个地方
I just want to go someplace where.
那里我不会想到别的事 除了奎迪
I won't think of nothing except him.
洛奇 让时间冲淡吧
Rocky, give it some time.
别这样做
Don't do this.
很多人都同样活在痛苦中
A lot of people live with hurt.
许多人没有选择
Adrian, a lot of people don't have the choice.
我有
I do.
而你愿意为此放弃所有东西？
And for that you're willing to lose everything?
艾莉 这并非所有
This ain't everything.
这房子 汽车 我们拥有的东西
This house and the stuff we have.
都不是所有
ain't everything.
还有许多东西的
There's a lot more than this.
之前你说要出赛
Before, there were reasons to fight.
我可以明白
I could understand.
但我今次不明白
But I don't understand this.
即使你赢了又如何？
Even if you win, what have you won?
阿波罗仍然死了
Apollo is still gone.
为何你不可改变你的想法？
Why can't you change your thinking?
每一个人都可以改变！
Everybody else does!
因为我是拳击手
Because I'm a fighter.
这就是我的处事方式
That's the way I'm made.
你嫁的就是这样的人
That's what you married.
我们无法改变自己
We can't change what we are.
不 你可以的
Yes, you can.
你无法改变什么的
You can't change anything.
我们只能按本性行事
All we can do is just go with what we are.
按本性行事
You cann't go with what we are.
你看过报章了吗？
Have you read the papers?
知道大家怎样说吗？
Do you know what everybody says?
是自杀！
Everybody says it's suicide!
你见过他 知道他多强壮
You've seen him. You know how strong he is.
你无法赢的
You can't win!
艾莉总是说出事实
Adrian always tells the truth.
对 或许我无法赢
Maybe I can't win.
或许我唯一可以做的
Maybe the only thing I can do.
是尽力攻击他
is just take everything he's got.
但若要打败我
But to beat me.
除非把我打死
he'll have to kill me.
而若要打死我
And to kill me.
他必要有胆量站在我面前
he'll have to have the heart to stand in front of me.
而要这样做
And to do that.
他必须愿意牺牲自己
he has to be willing to die himself.
我不知道他会否准备好这样做
I don't know if he's ready to do that.
我不知道
I don't know.
轻放那些格子皮箱
Be careful with the plaid ones.
他们是主人的
They belong to the boss.
保利 有带牙刷吗？
Did you pack your toothbrush?
烟迹会残留在牙齿上的
You know how tobacco stains your teeth.
我已说过 我已告诉你许多次
If I've told you once, I've told you a thousand times.
别插话
Stop busting my chops.
等我回来我会用电线绑住她
I'll have her wires tied when I get back.
你何时回来？
When will you be back?
很快
Pretty soon.
你害怕吗？
Are you scared?
- 不怕 - 不 你怕
- No. - Yes, you are.
有少许吧？
A little maybe?
你不会吗？
Wouldn't you be?
若一个巨人要打垮我
If a big giant man wanted to beat me up,
我会很害怕
I'd be real scared.
坦白说 有时候
The truth is, sometimes.
我真的会有少许怕
I do get a little scared.
当我在擂台上被狠揍
When I'm in that ring really getting hit.
而我的手痛得提不起来时
and my arms hurt so much I can't lift them.
我会想“天啊
I'm thinking, "God,
真希望他揍我下巴
I wish this guy would hit me on the chin,
那么我再也没有感觉”
so I don't feel nothing anymore."
然后你内心的另一面
Then there's another side that comes out.
却不是那么怕
that isn't so scared.
这另一面
It's another side.
就想去继续
that wants to take more.
想去继续多一个回合
that wants to go that one more round.
因为继续多一个
because by going that one more roundwhen.
你认为没可能的回合
you don't think you can.
往往可以改变你一生
That's what makes all the difference in your life.
你明白我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
我还想你记住一件事
Can you remember one more thing?
记住
Remember that.
爸爸认为你是世上最出色的孩子
Daddy thinks you're the best boy in the world.
无论怎样 爸爸一样爱你
And Daddy loves you, no matter what.
我要走了
I have to go now.
你要照顾自己
Will you take care of everything.
别忘记给你的机械人充电
Don't forget to feed your robot.
再见 宝贝
Bye, babe.
祝你好运
Good luck.
谢谢
Thanks.
快些 收费仪在跳
Come on! The meter's running!
这次飞行真可怕
What a horrendous flight.
这就是俄罗斯？也不是太落后
This is Russia? Don't look so tough.
鲍先生
Mr. Balboa.
我们准备送你到住处
We take you to quarters now.
太阳何时升起？
When does the sun come up?
这对我的鼻窦有害
This is detrimental to my sinuses.
天气每小时都变动
Weather changes hour to hour.
你必须要适应
Get used to it.
请上车
Get in car now.
路途很遥远的
We have very long trip.
他像是吸血殭尸的表兄
He sounds like Dracula's cousin.
算了 保利
Come on, Paulie.
符合你要求吗？
Like you requested, yes?
- 你要求这样荒芜的地方？- 是
- You requested this dumb location? - Yeah.
为什么？你打算养驯鹿吗？
Why? You planning to grow reindeer or something?
我只想远离世俗
I just wanted to get away from things.
你要求的设备
The equipment you requested.
就在仓库内
is in barn.
- 他们是谁？- 「他们」？
- Who are they? - "They"?
是委派给你的
They are assigned to you.
是你的官方监督人
Official chaperones.
你们去哪儿 他们就去哪儿
Where you go, they go.
这是个噩梦
I have a bad dream here.
- 保利 没问题的 - 没问题？
- It's okay. - It's okay?
这不是给人住的
This is below human standards.
连天线也没有 你得投诉
There's no antennas. You have to complain.
我们会发疯的
We'll crack out here.
我已按指示 为你提供了一切
You have everything I have been instructed to provide.
我们任务已完成
We are finished, yes?
你不投诉？
No sparring?
我不再需要了 保利
I don't think I need it anymore.
没有练拳手 没有电视 什么都没有？
No sparring? No TV? Nothing?
他在这里怎样训练？
How the heck is he supposed to train around here?
没有电视 怎样收看美式足球季后赛？
No TV. What about the Rose Bowl game?
我打赌一定也没有客房服务
No room service, I bet.
真希望他们把我的漫画送来
I hope they got my comics here.
这假期真叫人沮丧
What a depressing vacation.
岂有此理
Goddamn.
将军 朋友
Checkmate, friend.
- 洛奇 我可以进来吗？- 可以
- Champ, can I come up? - Sure.
你好吗？
How you doing?
很好
Pretty good.
这样的天气真难忍受
Some kind of weather we're having.
对 的确很冷
It's pretty rough.
但对于你来说却很适合
But for what you have to do it's good.
使你更坚强
Toughen you up.
或许吧
I guess so.
我知道你要自己在这儿做很多事
You'll have to do almost everything alone.
- 但是我不会离开你的 - 我知道
- but I'll be with you. - Yeah, I know.
阿波罗就像我的儿子
Apollo was like my son.
我抚养他
I raised him.
他死了
When he died.
部分的我也死了
part of me died.
但现在
But now.
你是唯一的人
you're the one.
只有你
You're the one that's.
会使他精神不灭 只有你
going to keep his spirit alive.You're the one.
可以证明他不是死得没价值的
that's going to make sure he didn't die for nothing.
他将要熬过难关
You'll have to go through hell.
这难关比你任何一个噩梦还要糟
worse than any nightmare you ever dreamed.
但最后
But in the end.
你会是屹立不倒的那个
I know you'll be the one standing.
我会尝试
I'll try.
你知道你要做什么
You know what you have to do.
尽力去做
Do it.
谢谢你 杜克
Thanks, Duke.
我无法再离开你
I couldn't stay away any more.
我很挂念你
I missed you.
我也挂念你
不论怎样 我都与你一起
I'm with you no matter what.
「不论怎样」？
"No matter what?"
不论怎样
No matter what.
全力以赴
No pain.
伊凡
Drago.
各位好 我们在特别地方 祝大家圣诞快乐
Hello, everybody, and Merry Christmas from a very unusual place.
这里是苏联的莫斯科
We're in Moscow in the Soviet Union.
我们是汤巴里和班艾尔
I'm Barry Tompkins along with Al Bandiero.
这将是拳击界史上 最不容错过的赛事
This promises to be the most-watched event in boxing history.
来自美国的铁马鲍洛奇
The iron horse from America, Rocky Balboa.
伊凡
Drago.
自从赌城的那次惨剧 阿波罗身亡后
Since that tragedy in Las Vegas and the death of Apollo Creed.
他就被冠以「天降的死神」这绰号
Drago has been nicknamed Death From Above.
台上站着是苏联总书记
The General Secretary of the Soviet.
及政治局常委们
and other members of the Politburo.
和其他已经就坐的成员 来观赏这场在莫斯科的
have made their way to their seats high above the ring here in Moscow.
我知你现在没空闲
I know you're busy just now.
但我想告诉你一些
but I want to tell you some things.
我从没说过的事
I never told you.
我知我有时做了
I know sometimes I act stupid.
和说了一些愚蠢的东西
and say stupid things.
但别人说「丢掉那个废物」时你仍留在我身边
But you kept me around when others would have said, "Drop that bum."
你使我仍有自尊
You give me respect.
这些话我很难说出口
It's hard for me to say these things.
因为那不是我的风格
because that ain't my way.
但若我可以做另一个人
but if I could just be someone else.
我会想做你
I'd want to be you.
因你充满了真心
You're all heart, man.
谢谢你 保利
Thanks, Paulio.
现在去好好教训那个家伙！
Now blast this guy's teeth out!
我会尽力
I'll try.
其中一位拳手已经开始进场
One of the fighters is starting to make his way toward the ring.
听听观众的叫声
Listen to this crowd!
完全是充满仇恨的
This borders on pure hatred.
洛奇毫无表情
Rocky's face absolutely like stone.
他非常集中精神
He is the picture of concentration.
这些嘘声似乎对他没半点影响
The booing crowd here does not seem to bother him one bit.
他今晚的眼神像是能穿透铅板
The champ has a look tonight that can burn through lead.
这些嘘声完全没有影响他
The booing crowd has absolutely no effect on the man.
他仍然非常集中精神
His concentration seems to be like stone.
那是我爸爸
That's my dad.
- 我们知道 - 你以为我们白痴的吗
- We know. - We're not nerds.
听听观众的喊声 像疯了般
Listen to this crowd. It sounds insane.
俄罗斯全国冠军出场了
Now the entrance of the Russian national champion.
伊凡 他代表了整个国家
Ivan Drago, a man with an entire country in his corner.
看看伊凡的表情
Look at the expression on the face of Ivan Drago.
他对观众的热情似乎无动于衷
He seems impervious to the madness of the crowd.
他就如将要爆发的火山
He's like a volcano just waiting to erupt.
伊凡冷静地跟总理点头示意
The Russian champion is amazingly cool as he acknowledges his premier.
我要指出这是一场非认可的赛事
I'd like to point out again this is a non-sanctioned fight.
这并非锦杯赛
This is not for the title.
并没被美国拳击委员会认可
The American boxing commission has not sanctioned this bout.
各位
Ladies and gentlemen.
真难以相信
It's unbelievable.
我从未见过这样怀有敌意的观众
I've never seen such a hostile crowd.
这景象真教人难以相信
It's an unbelievable sight to see.
他们面对面地站着
They're toe-to-toe.
伊凡比洛奇高大 这就是现代版的
The Russian towers above the American It's a true case of.
大卫对歌利亚
David and Goliath.
真难以置信的情况
The condition of both men is unbelievable.
我一定会打垮你
I must break you.
记得我说过我想做你吗？
Remember what I said back there about wanting to be you?
忘了它吧
Forget it.
谢谢你 保利
Thanks, Paulio.
别手下留情 要坚硬如石头
Take it straight to him and be a rock for me. Understand?
要坚强 别输
Be strong!
把他打败
All right? Take it to him.
- 全力以赴 - 全力以赴
- No pain. - No pain.
洛奇 努力
Do it!
铃声响了
There's the opening round bell.
洛奇走到擂台中央
Rocky comes into the center of the ring.
洛奇把伊凡逼到自己场角
The Russian way back into Balboa's corner now.
- 走出来 - 突破他
- Get out of there! - Let's go!
再一次 伊凡挥出刺拳
Once more, it's Drago backing up Rocky with a jab.
洛奇失去平衡
Balboa is not staying on balance.
因他被伊凡的刺拳击中
because of the Russian's long jab.
保护好自己
Brace yourself!
双手提起
Hands up!
- 揍他 - 立刻
- Charge him! - Now!
他似乎无法触及伊凡
He can't seem to touch the Russian!
洛奇向伊凡进攻
Rocky pounding away at the midsection of the Russian!
他竭尽所能狂揍
He hit him with everything he's got!
而伊凡只对着他微笑
Drago just smiled at him.
- 别停下来 - 继续出拳
- Keep chopping away! - Chop him down!
洛奇 加油
Come on, Rocky.
洛奇似乎遇到很大麻烦
Rocky Balboa is in serious trouble!
必须在未造成伤亡前中止比赛
They might have to stop this one before somebody gets killed.
打破他的节奏
Break his rhythm!
洛奇受伤了 他吵醒这个巨人
Rocky's hurt. He woke the sleeping giant.
现在自讨苦吃
Now he's paying the price.
伊凡挥出右拳把洛奇抛到15英尺外
A solid hand from Drago sends Rocky Balboa 15 feet across the ring!
洛奇倒下来
And the champ is down!
洛奇 快起来
Rocky, get up!
双手提起
Hand up.
伊凡继续狂揍鲍洛奇
Drago continuing to punish Rocky Balboa!
竭力不让他离开场角
Hejust will not let him out of that corner!
洛奇尽力赛完这一个回合
Rocky Balboa is just trying to get through this first round.
伊凡将洛奇如布偶般扔到自己的场角
The Russian just threw Balboa into his own corner like a rag doll.
对洛奇来说这是个漫长的回合
A tough first three minutes for Rocky.
不只面对无往不胜的对手
He's not only fighting what appears to be an invincible opponenthe's.
还有满怀敌意的观众
also fighting a very hostile crowd.
而俄国总理和政治局成员都在看着
The Russian Premier and most of the Politburo are looking on.
发生什么事？
What's happening out there?
他在赢
He's winning.
我见到三个他
I see three of him out there.
攻击中间那一个
Get the one in the middle.
对 揍中间那个
Right, hit the one in the middle.
你没有照我的话做
那个美国人矮小又软弱
软弱
打击他的勇气 攻击他 他就会丧失勇气
Take his heart. If you hurt him, you'll take his heart.
- 全力以赴 - 全力以赴
- No pain. - No pain.
打击他的勇气
Take his heart.
继续努力
Keep working!
铃声响了 比赛似乎是一面倒
There's the bell for round two. It's been a one-sided fight so far.
洛奇要赢必须靠些运气 他被狂揍
It will take more than luck for Rocky to survive this round.
洛奇向他挥出勾拳
Rocky's been hit with bombs.
躲闪 勾拳
Slip and hook!
洛奇竭力留在台上对付伊凡
Balboa trying to stay in the middle of the ring against the big Russian.
打他的头
Move the head!
做你要做的事 对付他
Do you get to do. Stay with him!
全力以赴
No pain!
洛奇
Rocky!
洛奇再次被击倒！他又起来了！
Balboa goes down again! Bounces right back up!
他快被打死了
He's getting killed!
洛奇不断捱着伊凡的重拳
Rocky Balboa has taken Ivan Drago's best punches so far.
他受伤流血
He's cut and bleeding,
但他仍站着继续比赛
but he's on his feet and on the run.
支持住
He's cut!
他死定了
He dead!
伊凡受伤了 严重的伤
The Russian's cut! It's a bad cut!
鲍洛奇现在反过来狂揍伊凡
Now it's Rocky Balboa coming after Ivan Drago!
不可思议 继续打他
Incredible! Get him!
伊凡不想放弃
The Russian wants to go on!
他抓住洛奇的喉咙
He grabs Balboa by the throat!
洛奇抓起伊凡
Balboa picks up the Russian.
如摔跤手般把他摔在地上
and throws him to the ground like a wrestler!
这真是场混战！
It's a gutter war!
莫斯科的拳赛完全不设限！
No holds barred in Moscow!
洛奇目前可能处于劣势
Rocky may be on the receiving end so far,
但他却全力出击
but he's here to fight!
这像变了一场私人激战
This is shaping up to be a personal war.
而此刻
Right now,
这成了街头拳击赛
it's anybody's boxing match.
你做得很好
You're doing good.
要是我自己不会做这么好
I couldn't do better myself.
你怎能这么做呢？
他根本不算什么… 软弱
- 你伤他很严重 - 是
- You got him hurt bad. - Yeah.
现在他开始担心 你伤了他！
Now he's worried. You cut him!
你伤了他！你打伤了他！
You hurt him! You hurt him!
看到吗？看到吗？
You see? You see?
他不是机器！他也是人！
He's not a machine! He's a man!
他不是人类
他就像是一块铁
你要打败他
You want it more than he does!
- 全力以赴 - 全力以赴
- No pain! - No pain!
好 别对他手下留情
Okay, Take it to him!
洛奇狠狠的一个右拳！
A big right hand by Rocky Balboa!
你做得很好
You're doing great.
你一路走过来了
You've come a long way.
- 揍他 - 立刻
- Charge him! - Now!
打他
Punch him!
放马过来
Come on!
有些观众为洛奇打气
A few cheers now for Balboa.
莫斯科突然支持洛奇
Suddenly Moscow is pro Rocky!
全力以赴
No pain.
继续打他
Keep taking it to him.
这场馆快要爆炸
Al, this place is ready to explode.
双方拳来拳往
Lethal punch after punch!
表现惊人的意志力
Amazing willpower!
双方都不放弃
Neither man backing off.
洛奇的决心
Rocky Balboa's determination.
开始令观众倒戈相向
is actually winning over the once-hostile crowd.
真想不到
This is incredible.
第几个回合？
What round is it?
十五 还有一个回合
Fifteenth. One more round.
已没什么可阻挡我们
There's no stopping us now.
这回合属于我们的
This is our round.
别停下来
No stopping now!
开始了就不要停下来
You start, and you don't stop!
要尽你所有的体力
All your strength!
能力和爱
All your power! All your love!
你拥有的一切
Everything you've got!
你训练这个白痴 他令我蒙羞
你听他们
我们的同胞为他欢呼… 白痴
赢
我会战胜
为我自己
你要把他击倒
To win, you have to knock him out!
你要不断挥拳直到无力为止
Punch till you can't punch no more!
你的一生就在这里
This is your whole life here!
击倒他
Knock him out.
马上去
Do it now!
铃声响了 战斗继续
There's the bell. The war is on.
这是最后一个回合
This is the last round.
最后决胜
To the end.
哪一位拳手
Which one of these fighters.
能在这回合胜出？
will be standing at the end of this round?
伊凡挥出狠狠的刺拳
Drago snaps out a stiff jab.
再一个
and another.
继续
Go on.
洛奇处于下风
Rocky taking punishment,
他企图避开他
trying to get inside!
他已完全耗尽力气
He's completely exhausted.
加油 攻击他
Come on, cut him.
你还在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
打他
Hit him!
放马过来
Come on, fight!
洛奇狂揍伊凡
Balboa is chopping the Russian down!
伊凡挥出右拳突袭洛奇
Drago's hard right hand stuns Rocky Balboa.
别倒下
Don't go down!
- 别倒下 - 走开
- Don't go down. - Go away.
不讲求技术策略
Forget technique. Forget strategy.
这是一场街头激斗
This is just a street fight.
问题是
It's a question.
谁的取胜心较大
of who wants it most.
- 他在做什么 - 他快赢了
- What is he doing? - He's winning!
打他身体
To the body!
加油
Come on!
洛奇
Rocky.
打破他的头
knock his head off!
洛奇 打破他的头
Rocky, knock his head off!
加油！干掉他
Come on! Finish him!
别停下来
Don't stop.
你可以做到的
You're gonna do it!
四
Four.
六
Six!
洛奇完成了不可能完成的事
Rocky Balboa has done the impossible.
观众都为他欢呼
and these people love it!
这真是一场混战
It is absolute pandemonium!
谢谢
Thank you.
我今晚到这里来
I came here tonight.
没期望过什么
and I didn't know what to expect.
我见到许多人憎恨我
I've seen a lot of people hating me.
我不知道怎么去反应
and I didn't knowwhat to feel about that.
所以我也不喜欢你们
so I guess I didn't like you much either.
在刚才比赛时
During this fight.
我见到许多变化
I seen a lot of changing.
你们对我的态度
the way you felt about me.
以及我对你们的感觉
and the way I felt about you.
这场馆里有两个拳手
In here, there were two guys.
互相残杀
killing each other.
但我想这比二千万还好
But I guess that's better than 20 million.
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is.
如果我可以改变
if I can change.
你也可以改变
and you can change.
人人都可以改变
everybody can change!
我想对我儿子说一句话
I just want to say one thing to my kid.
他应该在家里睡着了 孩子 圣诞快乐
who should be home sleeping. Merry Christmas, kid!
我爱你
I love you!